Inventory of the Alfonso Robelo C. papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Alfonso Robelo C. papers
1978-1990
92003
Robelo C., Alfonso (Robelo Callejas)
6 manuscript boxes (2.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, programmatic statements, agreements, memoranda, press releases, and printed matter, relating to the Nicaraguan revolution of 1979, political and human rights conditions in Nicaragua under the Sandinista government, activities of anti-Sandinista Nicaraguan resistance organizations, relations between these organizations and the United States government, the contra guerrilla war in Nicaragua, negotiations to end the war, and the Nicaraguan election of 1990. Photocopy.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1992.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
Originals in possession of: A. Robelo.
Biographical/Historical Note
Nicaraguan junta member, 1979-1980; subsequently leader of anti-Sandinista resistance movements.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection relates to the Nicaraguan revolution of 1979, political and human rights conditions in Nicaragua under the Sandinista government, activities of anti-Sandinista Nicaraguan resistance organizations, relations between these organizations and the United States government, the contra guerrilla war in Nicaragua, negotiations to end the war, and the Nicaraguan election of 1990.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Alianza Revolucionaria Democrática (Nicaragua); Movimiento Democrático Nicaragüense.; Unidad Nicaragüense Opositora.; Resistencia Nicaragüense (Organization); Civil rights--Nicaragua.; Guerrillas--Nicaragua.; Elections--Nicaragua.; United States--Foreign relations--Nicaragua.; Nicaragua--Foreign relations--United States.; Nicaragua--History--1979-1990.; Nicaragua--History--Revolution, 1979.
Collection Contents
- Alianza Revolucionaria Democrática (ARDE) speeches and activities file, 1982-1986. (Box 1)
  Includes speeches, articles, letters, and notes concerning ARDE and Edén Pastora.
  - Edén Pastora, 1982-1984 (Folder 1: 1)
  - ARDE, 1982-1984 (Folder 1: 2-4)
  - Robelo speeches, 1985-1986 (Folder 1: 5)
- Resistencia Nicaragüense and Movimiento Democratico Nicaragüense file, 1978-1989. (Box 2-3)
  Contains articles, memos, speeches, agreements, and other printed matter relating to anti-Sandinista Nicaraguan resistance organizations and the relations between these organizations and the United States government. Also contains material from the Resistencia Nicaragüense Directorate position held by Robelo, including meeting minutes, notes, articles, speeches, agendas, and proposals.
  - Resistencia Nicaragüense, 1987-1988 (Folder 2: 1-3)
  - Movimiento Democratico Nicaragüense, 1981-1988 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Ceasefire talks, Atlantic Coast Miskitos Indians, 1982-1987 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Resistencia Nicaragüense Directorate files, 1978-1989 (Box 3)
    - Negotiations, 1978-1979 (Folder 3: 1)
    - Government, 1979 (Folder 3: 2)
    - Agenda in Junta, 1979-1980 (Folder 3: 3)
    - Socialist International, 1981-1983 (Folder 3: 4)
    - Nicaragua, miscellaneous, 1978-1986 (Folder 3: 5)
    - Elections, 1984 (Folder 3: 6)
    - Resistencia Nicaragüense finances, 1987 (Folder 3: 7)
    - Peace Negotiations, 1987-1988 (Folder 3: 8)
    - Robelo activities, 1983-1989 (Folder 3: 9)
    - Bloque Opositor del Sur (B.O.S.), 1986-1989 (Folder 3: 10)
- Subject files, 1974-1990. (Box 4-6)
  Consists of correspondence, proposals, agreements, articles, meeting minutes, reports, memos, and newspaper clippings, mainly on organizations
  - ARDE, 1983-1984 (Folder 4: 1)
  - Frente Amplio Opositor (FAO), 1978 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional (FSLN) critiques, 1986-1988 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Programa de Gobierno, undated (Folder 4: 4)
  - Nicaragua Analyses, 1974-1988 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Human Rights, 1980-1988 (Folder 5: 1)
  - Unidad Nicaragüense Opositora and Europe, 1985-1989 (Folder 5: 2)
  - Elections, 1990 (Folder 5: 3)
  - Partido Social Democrata de Nicaragua (PSDN), 1979-1986 (Folder 5: 4)
  - PCDN and Coordinadora Democratica Nicaragüense (CDN), 1982 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Unidad Nicaragüense de Reconciliacion (UNIR), undated (Folder 5: 6)
  - U.S. Policy, 1984-1985 (Folder 6: 1)
  - Consejo Superior de la Empresa Privada (COSEP), 1981 (Folder 6: 2)
  - Coordinadora Democratica "Ramiro Sacasa Guerrero" (CDRSG), undated (Folder 6: 3)
  - Resistencia Nicaragüense, 1987-1988 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Frente Solidaridad Demócrata Cristiano (FSDC), Unión Democrática Nicaragüense-Fuerzas Armadas Revolucionarias Nicaragüenses (UDN-FARN), and Fuerza Democrática Nicaragüense (FDN), undated (Folder 6: 5)
  - Frente Sandinista de Liberación Nacional (FSLN), 1982 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Unidad Nicaragüense Opositora (UNO), 1985 (Folder 6: 7)